Deborah Rosenkranz Totten

600 Tuckahoe Boulevard, Richmond, Virginia 23226 804-833-7988

deborahrtotten@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A marketing professional, experienced in selling products ranging from credit cards to kindergarten, with several common threads throughout: strong work ethic, adeptness at juggling multiple projects, effective communication, and innovative problem solving. An energetic team player who loves achieving her goals – done well, on time and on budget.

EXPERIENCE

Collegiate School

Richmond, VA

Communications Coordinator, July 2018-Present

 As part of the four-person communications team, coordinate, design, edit and deploy internal and external communications across multiple platforms – email, paper and web – including database and list management.

Rainbow Station (Now LeafSpring School)

Richmond, VA

A regional chain of preschools and school-age recreation facilities (one corporate school, with an enrollment of roughly 250 children, and eleven franchise schools, in four states).

Marketing Manager, April 2014-July 2018

- Established a strategic annual marketing plan for five local schools, where none existed previously.
- Reduced the corporate marketing budget by 33% from year one to year two, while overall system revenue grew.
- Launched an initiative to improve Search Engine Optimization (SEO) and online reputation management--to take advantage of the powerful nature of parent referrals in feeding the schools' enrollment pipelines.
- Successfully planned and executed several large and complex events, including an annual franchise conference (met the challenge to reduce the cost of the conference by 50% from the year prior, while still meeting all strategic goals and maintaining attendee satisfaction).
- Redesigned the franchise sales portion of the website. Partnered with the corporate team to establish strategy, write content and have served as liaison with graphic designer and web developer.
- Wrote and helped to produce promotional videos.
- Manage the corporate social media presence and consult with the schools on their social media strategy and management.
- Collaborate with the web developer to refine and update the multiple school websites, as well as for new site development with the addition of new schools.
- Coach teachers and administrators at the schools on best practices for maintaining brand integrity.
- Have grown my proficiency in Adobe InDesign and, in the process, have saved the schools significant expense by creating assets in-house.
- Develop strategy and provide content to external designers for highly visible, high priority marketing materials.
- Produce branded newsletters templates on the Constant Contact platform (in lieu of a paper version) and train team members and franchisees to use the platform.
- Have been repeatedly recruited to employ strong project management skills to assist with projects in other areas of the business, including franchise development.

Royall & Company

Richmond, VA

Direct marketing firm that partners with college and university admissions offices to help them achieve their enrollment goals.

Strategic Leader, November 2004-December 2005

- Managed a team of eight people, including an art director, copywriter, web programmer, project manager, administrative assistant and two account managers.
- Established list strategy and creative direction for multiple large scale mail campaigns, both email and paper mail.
- Developed strong relationships with clients through continual contact, strategic communication and careful nurturing.
- Advised colleges and universities about strategic enrollment practices, beyond direct marketing.

Senior Account Manager, August 2002-November 2004

- Managed multiple direct marketing campaigns, both electronic and paper, to ensure timely and accurate deployments.
- Maintained friendly and productive client relationships.
- Served as the primary liaison between the clients and the information technology group in order to ensure timely and accurate deployments of programs.

First North American National Bank (FNANB),

Richmond, VA

Marketing Analyst, October 2000-August 2002

- Managed, from inception to completion, direct marketing campaigns to an average of 1.5 million potential credit card customers.
- Through analysis and sound testing methodologies, structured campaigns to increase the rate of response, typically achieving as much as 10% over budgeted response rates.
- Managed vendor relationships with a continuous goal to improve quality and efficiency, which ultimately reduced production cost by 50% through vendor competition and research.

Rainbow Station, Inc.

Richmond, VA

Administrative Assistant, May 1997-October 2000

EDUCATION

Mary Washington College, May 1995

Fredericksburg, VA

Bachelor of Arts, Studio Art

University of Richmond Coding Bootcamp, April-October 2018

Richmond, VA

OTHER INVOLVEMENT

Glenburnie Civic Association, January 2012-December 2013

Richmond, VA

President

American Marketing Association, January 2017-April 2018 Richmond, VA Member & Volunteer "Greeter"

SKILLS

Adobe InDesign, Illustrator and some Photoshop; HTML, CSS and beginning Javascript